[
    {
        "question": "In the line “……..she defiantly left Poland,” the word “defiantly” DOES NOT refer to",
        "optionA": "Coldly",
        "optionB": "Challenging",
        "optionC": "Resistant",
        "optionD": "Openly",
        "answer": "Openly"
    },

    {
        "question": "Marie …………………… by leaving Poland and travelling to France to enter the Sorbonne.",
        "optionA": "challenged authority",
        "optionB": "showed intelligence",
        "optionC": "got happy",
        "optionD": "was distressed",
        "answer": "challenged authority"

    },

    {
        "question": "The events in the life of Marie Curie could reveal the following points:",
        "optionA": "She was determined to receive higher education.",
        "optionB": "She was eager for women empowerment.",
        "optionC": "She had a brilliant mindset and rude behaviour.",
        "optionD": "She never liked her personal and professional life with Pierre Curie.",
        "answer": "She was determined to receive higher education."
    },

    {
        "question": "Even though she became fatally ill by working with radium, Marie Curie was never.",
        "optionA": "Cheerful ",
        "optionB": "Enthusiastic ",
        "optionC": "Staunch",
        "optionD": "Disillusioned",
        "answer": "Disillusioned"
    },

    {
        "question": "Marie became ‘aggrieved’ when she found that",
        "optionA": "Her husband was dead.",
        "optionB": "he University of Warsaw was closed for women.",
        "optionC": "She was ill.",
        "optionD": "She will have to leave her birthplace.",
        "answer": "Her husband was dead."
    },

    {
        "question": "Marie’s mother was …………………… and died after the death of",
        "optionA": "heartbroken, her friends",
        "optionB": "depressed, two of her daughters",
        "optionC": "heartbroken, one of her daughters",
        "optionD": "heartbroken, her cousin",
        "answer": "heartbroken, one of her daughters"
    },

    {
        "question": "Marie completed her master’s degree and a doctorate in physics from ……………………",
        "optionA": "University of Warsaw",
        "optionB": "University of Sorbonne",
        "optionC": "University of Poland",
        "optionD": "University of France",
        "answer": "University of Sorbonne"
    },

    {
        "question": "According to the passage, how long did the married life of Marie & Pierre Curie survive?",
        "optionA": "12 years",
        "optionB": "10 years",
        "optionC": "11 years",
        "optionD": "15 years",
        "answer": "11 years"
    },

    {
        "question": "What takes place in Hong Kong's Happy Valley?",
        "optionA": "Chicken Wrestling",
        "optionB": "Horse racing",
        "optionC": "Street Racing",
        "optionD": "Arm Wrestling",
        "answer": "Horse racing"
    },

    {
        "question": "Who painted the Mona Lisa?",
        "optionA": "Alexander Graham Bell",
        "optionB": "Sir Isaac Newton",
        "optionC": "Leonardo Da Vinci",
        "optionD": "Albert Einstein",
        "answer": "Leonardo Da Vinci"
    },

    {
        "question": "What’s the most important book in the Moslem religion?",
        "optionA": "The Koran",
        "optionB": "The Dictionary",
        "optionC": "The Bible",
        "optionD": "The Chemistry text Book",
        "answer": "The Koran"
    },

    {
        "question": "What’s the capital of Ethiopia?",
        "optionA": "Cape Town",
        "optionB": "San Francisco",
        "optionC": "Abuja",
        "optionD": "Syndey",
        "answer": "Addis Ababa"
    },

    {
        "question": "How many squares are there on a chess board?",
        "optionA": "128",
        "optionB": "64",
        "optionC": "32",
        "optionD": "256",
        "answer": "64"
    },

    {
        "question": "Who invented the electric light bulb?",
        "optionA": "Tom Cruise",
        "optionB": "Barack Obama",
        "optionC": "Wole Soyinka",
        "optionD": "Thomas Edison",
        "answer": "Thomas Edison"
    },

    {
        "question": "What are the first three words of the bible?",
        "optionA": "be with everyone",
        "optionB": "Again Jesus asked",
        "optionC": "In the beginning",
        "optionD": "At that time",
        "answer": "In the beginning"
    }
]